Guide to the Lois Stifel collection of tobacco ephemera, 1880-2019 and undated RL.11677
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Lois Stifel collection of tobacco ephemera
1880-2019 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Stifel, Lois
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11677
12.0 Linear Feet
Collection includes print advertisements, accessories and merchandise catalogs, collector newsletters, direct mailings, cigarette and tobacco labels and packaging, point of sale displays, sheet music, memorabilia and collectibles, tobacco tins, smoking and smoking cessation paraphernalia, juvenile and adult literature, research reports and articles on smoking and health and other printed materials, along with audio and video cassettes and optical discs. Materials primarily relate to smoking, tobacco use and prevention in the United States but some international examples are also present. Materials also relate to the tobacco industry in North Carolina. Companies represented include Alfred Dunhill, American Cancer Society, American Legacy Foundation, American Lung Association, American Tobacco Company, Brown & Williamson, Liggett & Myers, National Cancer Institute, National Institutes of Health (NIH), Philip Morris, R.J. Reynolds, Tobacco Institute, U.S. Surgeon General and Zippo. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Advertising; Artifacts and Memorabilia; Cigarette and Tobacco Packaging; Printed Materials; Audiovisual Materials.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
However, original audiovisual materials are closed until use copies can be produced.
A selection of published print materials has been removed from the collection and cataloged separately. Consult the Duke University Libraries catalog for these titles.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Lois Stifel collection of tobacco ephemera was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2017-2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Charles McKinney papers
Garrett Orr papers
Howard Scott papers
Irving Sonn papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Competitive Advertisements
J. Walter Thompson Company. Dan Seymour papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Domestic Advertisements
J. Walter Thompson Company. Loy Baxter papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Review Board records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Shirley F. Woodall papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Thomas Sutton papers
Liggett & Myers Tobacco Company records
Outdoor Advertising Association of America slide library
Ralph Rydholm papers
Richard Pollay Tobacco Industry Promotion (TIPS) collection
Tobacco Advertisements collection
Collection Overview
Collection includes print advertisements, accessories and merchandise catalogs, collector newsletters, direct mailings, cigarette and tobacco labels and packaging, point of sale displays, sheet music, memorabilia and collectibles, tobacco tins, smoking and smoking cessation paraphernalia, juvenile and adult literature, research reports and articles on smoking and health and other printed materials, along with audio and video cassettes and optical discs. Materials primarily relate to smoking, tobacco use and prevention in the United States but some international examples are also present. Materials also relate to the tobacco industry in North Carolina. Companies represented include Alfred Dunhill, American Cancer Society, American Legacy Foundation, American Lung Association, American Tobacco Company, Brown & Williamson, Liggett & Myers, National Cancer Institute, National Institutes of Health (NIH), Philip Morris, R.J. Reynolds, Tobacco Institute, U.S. Surgeon General and Zippo. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- Tobacco; Tobacco; Tobacco industry -- United States; Tobacco industry -- North Carolina; Tobacco package labels -- United States; Smoking -- United States; Smoking; Cigarette industry -- United States; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; American Tobacco Company; Brown & Williamson; Liggett & Myers Tobacco Company; Philip Morris Incorporated; R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Company; Tobacco Institute (Washington, D.C.); United States. Public Health Service
- Advertising, 1898-2015 and undated; 1
  - Mounted Advertisements, 1917-1996 and undated; 1
    - Ann Landers, Time Has Come to Snuff Out Smoking, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Camel, Joe Camel, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Chesterfield, 1931-1952; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Kool, 1942 (Box 1)
    - Lucky Strike, 1928-1948; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Lucky Strike (Santa Claus), 1952 and undated (Box 1)
    - Marlboro, 1944-1951 (Box 2)
    - Murad, undated (Box 2)
    - Philip Morris, 1942-1943 (Box 2)
    - Raleigh, 1929 (Box 2)
    - Regent, 1942 (Box 2)
    - Benson & Hedges, 1970 (Box 3)
    - Bull Durham, 1968 (Box 3)
    - Camel, 1929-1945 and undated (Box 3)
    - Chesterfield, 1917-1943 (Box 4)
    - Chesterfield, 1944-1949 (Box 5)
    - Edgeworth Pipe Tobacco, 1946 (Box 5)
    - Fatima, 1929 (Box 5)
    - Kent, 1964 (Box 5)
    - L&M, 1971 (Box 5)
    - Lucky Strike, 1928-1942 (Box 5)
    - Lucky Strike, 1943-1960s (Box 6)
    - Old Gold, 1939-1950 (Box 6)
    - Philip Morris, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Princess Gardner (accessories), 1957 (Box 6)
  - Point of Purchase Displays, 1987-2000 and undated; 2
    - Alpine--All the Pleasure--for Less!, 1999 (Box 21)
    - Basic--The Best Things in Life Are Basic, 1999 (Box 7)
    - Camel Cash Ticketmaster, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Camel Metro Active, 1997 (Box 7)
    - Camel Mighty Tasty Lifestyles!, 1998 (Box 7)
    - Marlboro Chili Roundup contest, 2000 (Box 7)
    - Marlboro Mild A New Menthol survey, 2000 (Box 7)
    - Marlboro Unlimited All New Gear, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Marlboro Unlimited Gear Without Limits, 1995 (Box 7)
    - Camel Buy 2 Packs Get 1 Free! Pleasure to Burn, 2000 (Box 8)
    - Camel Turkish Jade Lights, undated (Box 8)
    - Kamel Originals, 1996 (Box 8)
    - Marlboro Cowboy's Place 1 Million Prizes, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Marlboro Get a Ride Win a Trip to Marlboro Racing School, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Newport "Alive with Pleasure!" sign, 1987 (Box 8)
    - Philip Morris USA.com Our Web Site A Message for Smokers, 2000 (Box 8)
    - Seven Seas Smoking Tobacco (John Weisert Tobacco Company), undated (Box 8)
    - Virginia Slims Special Offer/Special Price signs, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Winston No Bull 5 Want to Win a Million? Real Money for Real Fans, 1999 (Box 8)
  - Point of Purchase Literature, 1995-2002 and undated; 3
    - Alpine--New! All the Pleasure for Less, 1999 (Box 9)
    - Camel--Camel Cash Groove Blender Mixers Guide: Get In the Groove, 1996 (Box 9)
    - Camel--New Camel Turkish Jade, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Marlboro--2 Free Packs When You Buy 3, 1998 (Box 9)
    - Marlboro--Chili Roundup, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Marlboro--Cowboy Chronicles Gear catalog offer, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Marlboro--Cowboy's Place, 1999 (Box 9)
    - Marlboro--Marlboro Milds a New Menthol, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Marlboro--Marlboro Unlimited Gear, 1995 (Box 9)
    - Marlboro--Marlboro Unlimited Gear Built for Adventure, 1996-1997; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Marlboro--Marlboro Unlimited Get on Board, 1995 (Box 9)
    - Marlboro--Party at the Marlboro Ranch, 1998 (Box 9)
    - Marlboro--Ranch Party Continues in '99, 1998 (Box 9)
    - Marlboro--Unlimited Premier Issue magazine offer, 1996 (Box 9)
    - Marlboro--Win a Trip to the Marlboro Racing School, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Newport--Pleasure! Fire It Up!, undated (Box 9)
    - Original Orphan Boy Smoking Tobacco (John Weisert Tobacco Co.), undated (Box 9)
    - Philip Morris--Our Business. Our Values. Our Programs. Our Website., 2000 (Box 9)
    - Winston--Free 1999 Winston Cup Racing Schedule, 1998 (Box 9)
    - Winston--Get in the Race. Win $1,000,000, 1998 (Box 9)
    - Winston--Go for It, 1998 (Box 9)
    - Winston--Looks Like Everybody Wants to Win a Million, 1998 (Box 9)
    - Winston--Want to Win a Million?, 1999 (Box 9)
  - Print Advertisements, 1898-2015 and undated; 4
    - Alpine, 1989-1990 (Box 9)
    - Amphora (pipe tobacco), 1975 (Box 9)
    - Barclay, 1982-1983 (Box 9)
    - Benson & Hedges, 1977-1984 (Box 9)
    - Blu, 2015 (Box 9)
    - Bright, 1982-1983 (Box 9)
    - Bucks, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Bull Durham, 1991 (Box 9)
    - Camel, 1943-2013 (Box 9)
    - Camel--Joe Camel, 75th anniversary poster, 1988 (Box 20)
    - Camel--"Mighty Tasty" Camel Lights poster, 1998 (Box 20)
    - Camel--NASCAR/NHRA racing poster, 1995 (Box 20)
    - Camel--Pleasure to Burn, 1999-2005 (Box 9)
    - Capri, 1989-1995 (Box 9)
    - Carlton, 1977-1994 (Box 9)
    - Chase National Bank--Who Backs the Packs?, 1952 (Box 9)
    - Chesterfield, 1935-1948 (Box 9)
    - Decade, 1977-1978 (Box 9)
    - Doral, 1975-2003 (Box 9)
    - Eclipse, 2004 (Box 9)
    - Eve, 1983 (Box 9)
    - GPC, 1998 (Box 9)
    - Jade, 2001-2002 (Box 9)
    - Kent, 1977-1984 (Box 9)
    - Kool, 1976-2002 (Box 9)
    - L&M, 1976-1983 (Box 9)
    - Lark, 1976 (Box 9)
    - London Life, 1916 (Box 9)
    - Lucky Strike, 1954-1984 (Box 9)
    - Magna, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Malibu, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Marlboro, 1977-1999 (Box 9)
    - Marlboro Unlimited poster, 1995 (Box 20)
    - Max, 1977 (Box 9)
    - Melachrino (Camel on back side), 1926 (Box 9)
    - Merit, 1977-1988 (Box 9)
    - Misty, 1993-1999 (Box 9)
    - Montclair, 1990 (Box 9)
    - More, 1976-1986 (Box 9)
    - Murad, 1915 (Box 9)
    - Newcig, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Newport, 1976-2014 (Box 9)
    - Nicorette (smoking cessation product), 2007 (Box 9)
    - Omni, 2001-2002 (Box 9)
    - Pall Mall, 1975-2007 (Box 9)
    - Philip Morris, 1940s (Box 9)
    - Players, 1984-1986 (Box 9)
    - Prince Albert, 1900s (Box 9)
      Scope and Contents
      Features American Horse (D. 1908), Native American spokesperson
    - Real, 1977 (Box 9)
    - Richmond Gem, 1898 (Box 9)
    - Ritz, 1986 (Box 9)
    - RJ Reynolds Industries, 1976 (Box 9)
    - Ronson (lighter), 1945 (Box 9)
    - Salem, 1975-1984 (Box 9)
    - Saratoga, 1976 (Box 9)
    - Smoker's Warehouse Club, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Sterling, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Stride, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Tall, 1976-1977 (Box 9)
    - Tareyton, 1975-1977 (Box 9)
    - TRUE, 1975-1985 (Box 9)
    - Vantage, 1977-1988 (Box 9)
    - Viceroy, 1983-1989 (Box 9)
    - Virginia Slims, 1978-2000 (Box 9)
    - Winston, 1975-2002 (Box 9)
    - Winston--Charlotte Motor Speedway posters, 1988, 1997 (Box 20)
    - Zippo (lighter), 1984-1996 (Box 9)
    - Alpine, 1964 (Box 10)
    - American Cancer Society--Peggy Fleming, 1968 (Box 10)
    - ASR (lighters), 1949-1952 (Box 10)
    - Belair, 1971 (Box 10)
    - Benson & Hedges, 1971-1972 (Box 10)
    - Camel, 1927-2000 (Box 10)
    - Camel/Prince Albert (Santa Claus), 1936 (Box 10)
    - Chesterfield, 1931-1968; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Chesterfield (Santa Claus), 1941-1949 (Box 10)
    - Consul, 1969 (Box 10)
    - Doral, 1998-2003 (Box 10)
    - Dr. Grabow (pipe), 1965 (Box 10)
    - Duke (includes replicas of 1916 ads), 1954-1959 (Box 10)
    - El Producto, 1968 (Box 10)
    - Evans (accessories), 1948 (Box 10)
    - Eve, 1976 (Box 10)
    - Fatima, 1951 (Box 10)
    - Fleetwood, 1942-1943 (Box 10)
    - Gold Label (cigars), 1969 (Box 10)
    - Heritage (accessories), 1965 (Box 10)
    - Imperial (Kaufman Bros., pipe), 1942 (Box 10)
    - Kamel, 1997 (Box 10)
    - Kaywoodie (pipes and accessories), 1942-1965 (Box 10)
    - Kent, 1965-1972 (Box 10)
    - King Sano, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Kool, 1938-1997 (Box 10)
    - L&M, 1960-1977 (Box 10)
    - La Palina (cigars), 1968 (Box 10)
    - Lark, 1968-1976 (Box 10)
    - Lord Buxton (accessories), 1959 (Box 10)
    - Lucky Strike, 1930-2000; 3 folders (Box 10)
    - Marlboro, 1959-1969 (Box 10)
    - Masterpiece, 1965 (Box 10)
    - Montclair, 1964 (Box 10)
    - Newport, 1963-1965 (Box 10)
    - Nicorette (smoking cessation product), 2002 (Box 10)
    - Old Gold, 1930-1971 (Box 10)
    - Pall Mall, 1949-1971 (Box 10)
    - Parliament, 1970 (Box 10)
    - Philip Morris, 1944-1961 (Box 10)
    - Players, 1928 (Box 10)
    - Prince Albert, 1942-1945 and undated (Box 10)
    - Robt. Burns (cigars), 1958 (Box 10)
    - Ronson (lighter), 1952-1969 (Box 10)
    - Salem, 1964-1972 (Box 10)
    - Shakespeare (cigars), 1969 (Box 10)
    - Silva Thins, 1976 (Box 10)
    - Swank (accessories), 1959 (Box 10)
    - Tareyton, 1949-1970 (Box 10)
    - Tempo, 1965 (Box 10)
    - The Pipe, 1969 (Box 10)
    - TRUE, 1971-1976 (Box 10)
    - Various--Advertising with celebrities smoking, 1935-1966 (Box 10)
      Includes: Booth Tarkington (Grenville Kleiser's Mail Course in English); Frances D. Roosevelt (Portrait of the Author of Lend-Lease); Walter Cronkite (CBS Radio Network)
    - Viceroy, 1963-1972 (Box 10)
    - Virginia Slims, 1971 (Box 10)
    - Waterford, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Weber (pipes), 1969 (Box 10)
    - Webster (cigars), 1947 (Box 10)
    - Wee Willem (cigars), 1969 (Box 10)
    - Winston, 1968-2002 (Box 10)
    - York, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Zippo (lighter), 1963-2002 (Box 10)
- Artifacts and Memorabilia, 1950s-2014 and undated; 2
  - Collectibles, 1950S-2014 and undated; 5
    - Basic playing cards, undated (Box 11)
    - Benson & Hedges playing card set, undated (Box 13)
    - Bleacher cushion, Winston Cup Series NASCAR; Crown/Skoal Classic Racing, Fast Fare, Zippy Mart, 1985 (Box 11)
    - Bucks playing cards, undated (Box 11)
    - Camel cigarette case, undated (Box 11)
    - Camel Jimmy Spencer #23 replica race car, 1997 (Box 11)
    - Camel promotion "Camiseta gratis" free t-shirt (box in Spanish), 1988 (Box 11)
    - Cocktail napkins, 2005 and undated (Box 13)
      Includes: Camelsmokes.com; Marlboro "come to where the flavor is"; Marlboro M
    - CVS/pharmacy The Last Pack tobacco quit-kit, 2014 (Box 11)
    - Gold leaf pin given to members of Congress by the Tobacco Institute, undated (Box 11)
    - Golden Lights playing cards, undated (Box 11)
    - Kool promotion House Rewards CD opener with pack of cigarettes, 2000 (Box 11)
    - License plates, 1995 and undated (Box 13)
      Includes: NASCAR Winston Cup Series; RJ Reynolds "Pride in Tobacco" and "Tobacco Pays My Bills"
    - Light-Free Smokeless Cigarettes (UltraTech Corp., Dresher Pa.), undated (Box 11)
    - Nebo Cigarettes collector cloth, flags of countries, undated (Box 21)
      Includes: Poland, Portugal, Russia, Servia
    - Pall Mall cigarette case, undated (Box 11)
    - Prime American Value Selection playing cards, undated (Box 11)
    - Private Stock playing cards, undated (Box 11)
    - Red Man chewing tobacco metal box, 1989 (Box 11)
    - Rubber stamp, Liggett & Myers Incorporated, 4121 Folsom Ave, St. Louis Mo., undated (Box 11)
    - Smoking Sambo novelty, approximately 1950s (Box 13)
    - Tube Rose Snuff fan, undated (Box 13)
    - Vantage golf championship mug, undated (Box 11)
    - Winston Jimmy Spencer #23 Gold replica race car, 1999 (Box 11)
    - Winston Jimmy Spencer #23 No Bull replica race car, 1999 (Box 11)
    - Winston NASCAR Winston Cup Series mug, undated (Box 11)
    - Winston playing cards, undated (Box 11)
    - Zira Cigarettes--Collector cloth, flags and songs of countries, undated (Box 21)
      Includes national flags and a verse of the national hymn, song, air or anthem, or patriotic/folk tune. Countries represented: Brazil, Bulgaria, China, Cuba, Egypt, Japan, Poland, Scotland, Sweden, Switzerland, Wales
  - Small Memorabilia, 1973-2005 and undated; 6
    - Button--Anti-smoking (No smoking sign), undated (Box 12)
    - Button--Anti-smoking--American Cancer Society--Bear "Be Beary Healthy Please Don't Smoke", undated (Box 12)
    - Button--Anti-smoking--American Cancer Society--Flowers "Smoking Stinks", undated; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Button--Anti-smoking--American Cancer Society--Frog "Kiss Me I Don't Smoke", undated; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Button--Anti-smoking--American Lung Association "Thanks for Not Smoking", undated (Box 12)
    - Button--Anti-smoking--I Have Chosen Not to Smoke, undated (Box 12)
    - Button--Bucks "Ask for Bucks", undated (Box 12)
    - Button--Liggett & Myers Open Tournament Players U.S. Professional Match Play Tournament (golf), undated (Box 12)
    - Button--Winston Is Racing, undated (Box 12)
    - Button--Yours Cigarettes Cheaper Than Theirs, undated (Box 12)
    - Candy cigarettes--Chesterfield, undated (Box 12)
    - Candy cigarettes--Pall Mall, undated (Box 12)
    - Candy cigarettes--Stark Stryke, undated (Box 12)
    - Cigarette case--More, undated (Box 12)
    - Coasters--Camel Pool League, 1997 (Box 12)
    - Coasters--Camelsmokes.com, 2005 (Box 12)
    - Coasters--Camel Turkish Gold, 2001 (Box 12)
    - Coasters--L&M Cigarettes, undated (Box 12)
    - Coasters--Lucky Strike, LS/MFT Lucky Strikes Again, The Moment Is Right for It, undated (Box 12)
    - Collector card--Topps Chewing Gum; Take a "Lucky Stride" Away from These Cigarettes. Warning: Smoking Wacky Packages May Be Harmful to Your Health, 1979 (Box 12)
    - Collector card--W. Duke and Sons, Duke Cigarettes; Floral Beauties and Language of Flowers series: Fuchsia=Taste, undated (Box 12)
    - Collector card--W. Duke and Sons, Duke Cigarettes; Floral Beauties and Language of Flowers series: Wild English Daisy=Daintiness, undated (Box 12)
    - Collector cloth--Brown University. Includes alma mater song, yell, seal, flag, bear, undated (Box 12)
    - Collector cloth--Nebo Cigarettes--Algeria, undated (Box 12)
    - Collector cloth--Nebo Cigarettes--Canada, undated; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Collector cloth--Nebo Cigarettes--Cuba, undated (Box 12)
    - Collector cloth--Nebo Cigarettes--England, undated (Box 12)
    - Collector cloth--Nebo Cigarettes--Ireland, undated (Box 12)
    - Collector cloth--Nebo Cigarettes--Italy, undated (Box 12)
    - Collector cloth--Nebo Cigarettes--Panama, undated (Box 12)
    - Collector cloth--Nebo Cigarettes--Russia, undated; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Collector cloth--Nebo Cigarettes--Scotland, undated; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Collector cloth--Nebo Cigarettes--Sweden, undated (Box 12)
    - Collector cloth--Nebo Cigarettes--Zion, undated (Box 12)
    - Collector rug--Luxury Cigarettes--Blue, undated (Box 12)
    - Collector rug--Luxury Cigarettes--Red, undated (Box 12)
    - Filters--De-Nicotea, undated (Box 12)
    - Filters--Medico, undated (Box 12)
    - Folding mirror--Joe Camel "It's for You", 1990 (Box 12)
    - Key chain--Joe Camel, undated (Box 12)
    - Magnets--Anti-smoking--American Cancer Society--Great American Smokeout Third Thursday in November, undated; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Magnets--Anti-smoking--Please No Puffin, Alaska, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Magnets--Anti-smoking--Thanks for Not Smoking; Ellen Edith, Santa Cruz, Calif., undated (Box 12)
    - Pin--Tie pin Liggett Group, undated (Box 12)
    - Pin--Tobacco leaf, undated (Box 12)
    - Pocket protector--Chesterfield, undated (Box 12)
    - Pocket protector--Liggett & Myers, undated (Box 12)
    - Wooden nickel--Liggett & Myers welcomes you to the Iowa State Convention, 1973 (Box 12)
- Cigarette and Tobacco Packaging, 1975-2003 and undated; 3
  - Apollo/Soyuz commemorative brand (Russia), 1975 (Box 14)
  - Buckhorn cigarette case, undated (Box 14)
  - Bugler cigarette case, undated (Box 14)
  - Bugler rolling tobacco, undated (Box 14)
  - Bull Durham smoking tobacco and papers, undated (Box 14)
  - Bull Durham smoking tobacco retailer box, undated (Box 21)
  - Camel 20's, undated (Box 15)
  - Camel Filters, 75th birthday limited edition, 1988 (Box 15)
  - Camel Turkish Gold, undated (Box 15)
  - Camel Turkish Gold, Buy 1 Get 1 Free, 2003 (Box 15)
  - Camel Turkish Jade Lights, Buy 1 Get 1 Free, 2003 (Box 15)
  - Camel Wides, undated (Box 15)
  - Chesterfield 101 Filters, undated (Box 15)
  - Chesterfield tin, undated (Box 14)
  - Emperor's Taste Golden Camellias (China), undated (Box 15)
  - Eve Lights Slim 100's, 1992 (Box 15)
  - Eve Slim Lights 100's, undated (Box 15)
  - Flying Horse (China), undated (Box 15)
  - Glory Menthol, undated (Box 15)
  - Hengta Brand (China), undated (Box 15)
  - Kamel Red Lights, approximately 1996 (Box 15)
  - Lucky Strike Flat Fifties cigarette tin, undated (Box 14)
  - Kite Mentholated Cigarette Tobacco, undated (Box 14)
  - Peony 100's (China), undated (Box 15)
  - Philip Morris Special Blend tin, undated (Box 14)
  - Pure Full Flavor (Tuscarora Indian Nation), undated (Box 15)
  - Pure Lights (Tuscarora Indian Nation), undated (Box 15)
  - Pure Menthol (Tuscarora Indian Nation), undated (Box 15)
  - R.A. Patterson Tobacco Co. Lucky Strike Cut Plug tin, undated (Box 14)
  - Shanghai (China), undated (Box 15)
  - Top Cigarette Tobacco, undated (Box 14)
  - Troika (Russia), undated (Box 15)
  - Vegas Full Flavor, undated (Box 15)
  - Vegas Lights, undated (Box 15)
  - Velvet--box for pocket tins, undated (Box 13)
  - Velvet Pipe and Cigarette Tobacco tin, undated (Box 14)
  - Winston 40th anniversary commemorative edition pack in replica tin, 1994 (Box 14)
- Printed Materials, 1880-2019 and undated; 4
  - Al Jaffee (Mad Magazine)--Some Mad Devices for Safer Smoking, 1964 (Box 16)
  - Alfred Dunhill--De-Nicotea Filters; U.S. Patents 1,985,840 and 2,215, 620: Designs for Tobacco Filters, 1934, 1940 (Box 16)
  - American Cancer Society--Sign: Smoking is very glamorour/Best tip yet: Don't start!, undated (Box 16)
  - American Cancer Society/Lindsay R. Curtis--The Story of a Cigarette coloring book, 1971 (Box 16)
  - American Legacy Foundation--"Truth" anti-smoking articles and stickers, 2001-2010 (Box 16)
  - American Tobacco Company--Price list: Antonio y Cleopatra cigars, 1969 (Box 16)
  - American Tobacco Company--Price list: Cigarettes, cigarette papers, smoking and chewing tobacco, 1969 (Box 16)
  - American Tobacco Company--Price list: International cigar brands, 1966 (Box 16)
  - American Tobacco Company--Sales Organization book, 1938 (Box 16)
  - Basic--The Best Things in Life Are Basic sweepstakes, 1999-2001 (Box 16)
  - Basic--Best Things catalog, 2000-2002 (Box 16)
  - Benson & Hedges--Direct mail, 1966-1999 (Box 16)
  - Bill Lueder (Isthmus, Madison, Wisc.)--Tommy Thompson and Tobacco, 1997 (Box 21)
  - Bones Bourcier (Stock Car Racing magazine)--Tobacco and Racing, 1997 (Box 16)
  - Brandstand (cigarette collectibles newsletter), 2002-2016; 12 folders (Box 16)
  - British American Tobacco Company--About Us, 2000 (Box 16)
  - Brown & Williamson--A Tour of Historic Louisville, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Brown & Williamson--Direct mail, 1997 (Box 16)
  - Brown & Williamson--Kool Presidential Guide, 1960 (Box 16)
  - Brown & Williamson--The Power to Grow: 1998 Annual Review (Box 16)
  - Cambridge--Direct mail, 1996 (Box 16)
  - Camel--Back Alley Gazette, 2004 (Box 21)
  - Camel--Camel Cash catalogs, 1991-2000 (Box 16)
  - Camel--CML: Camel Quarterly, 2000 (Box 16)
  - Camel--CML City Edition, 2001 (Box 16)
  - Camel--CML City Edition, 2001 (Box 21)
  - Camel--Direct mail, 1994-2014; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Camel--Direct mail, 2000 (Box 19)
  - Camel--Direct mail "Pleasure to Burn", 2000-2005 (Box 16)
  - Camel--E-mail, 2002-2003 (Box 16)
  - Camel--E-mail coupon offer, 2014 (Box 16)
  - Camel--Travel diary, 1995 (Box 16)
  - Camel/Circle K--Direct mail, 2010 (Box 16)
  - Carlton--Direct mail, 1997 (Box 16)
  - CDC (Centers for Disease Control and Prevention)--Highlight on cigarette warning labels, 2000 (Box 16)